<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jack of All Trades</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Jack of All Trades</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</managingEditor><webMaster>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 16:43:36 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://2e0byo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reroofing a concrete shed</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/building/shed-roof/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 16:43:36 +0200</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/building/shed-roof/</guid><description>We have a brick built shed with a concrete roof, which serves me as workshop. Unfortunately when we moved in the torched on felt (the proper three-layer system) had died in a large part, and water could make its way inside. Thus it needed re-roofing.
Now, whilst I have no experience roofing beyond tacking down felt on wooden roofs (which is infinitely simpler than what ended up happening), I immediately decided to volunteer to re-roof it if the landlord would pay.</description></item><item><title>Overzealous Zip Repair</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/zip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 16:09:50 +0200</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/zip/</guid><description>What do you do with a broken zipper? Especially early in the morning (i.e. around 1am).
Here is one way to repair a zip, preserving the latching effect to stop it falling down by itself. The wire rope (from ordinary copper stranded hookup wire) pulls the latching tooth, and the fairlead (made from two very small screws and some more wire soldered in place) converts enough of the tension into downwards force to move the zip.</description></item><item><title>Sunrise Lamp</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/sunrise-lamp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 13:28:58 +0200</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/sunrise-lamp/</guid><description>Every project is a prototype, which calls out for a second version avoiding the mistakes of the former. The trick is to give the prototypes away; then one has a legitimate excuse to make another&amp;mdash;and one gains an (undeserved) reputation for generosity to boot. After the quick sunrise alarm clock various things happened, including a &amp;lsquo;two week lockdown&amp;rsquo; to build up capacity in the NHS, which turned into three months. Thus I was stuck in one part of London, and my fiancée in another, and the streets were patrolled by Dobermans with £10,000 fine notices stuck to their teeth.</description></item><item><title>Wedding Carpentry</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/wedding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 18:01:17 +0200</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/wedding/</guid><description>Due to measures to combat the epidemic of bigamous marriages or something of the kind, we ended up having a wedding reception in the garden. Thus we needed tables, and benches, and things of the kind. Time to put the workbench to work.
Firstly there was a lorry:
Then there was a lot of wood:
The short pieces are legs for the benches; the longer will become benches and trestles (and will replace these horrible trestles I made earlier).</description></item><item><title>Carpentry Workbench</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/workbench2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 19:14:29 +0200</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/workbench2/</guid><description>The first shot at a workbench sat dormant for a fair while. Meanwhile it got cold&amp;mdash;very very cold. Then it got wet&amp;mdash;very very wet. Then it got hot&amp;mdash;very very hot. And how did my nice, carefully chosen unwarped 1&amp;quot; planks look after that? A pretty sorry state. Even the laminated legs had moved slightly (next time for lamination I need more glue). Then I discovered that I could get 6x2s from MKM building supplies.</description></item><item><title>Reverse Engineering a Fridge: Part 2</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/reverse-engineering-fridge2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 15:42:44 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/reverse-engineering-fridge2/</guid><description>Hardware So we have five mains circuits: the lamp, the fan, the heaters, the compressor, and the &amp;lsquo;superfreeze&amp;rsquo; button, which I think just adds the starting coils permanently. The original controller only switches four of these on the board (the superfreeze is a manual switch), and uses triacs for all except the compressor, which has a 10A relay. Of course, that requires the controller to be attached to the AC neutral, which isn&amp;rsquo;t a great idea with exposed hardware like a prototype balanced on a fridge.</description></item><item><title>Reverse Engineering a Fridge</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/reverse-engineering-fridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:36:37 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/reverse-engineering-fridge/</guid><description>We have a Hotpoint FFA52 fridge-freezer. It has previously given much hardship. It no longer works. Here is a graph of a non-working freezer:
I don&amp;rsquo;t mind a bit of swing in the temperature, but that&amp;rsquo;s all over the place. In the meantime the fridge compartment turned into a freezer, albeit not a very good one. Time to take it apart and see what the problem could be.</description></item><item><title>Cleaning Scanned Pdfs</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/cleaning-scanned-pdfs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 18:01:04 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/cleaning-scanned-pdfs/</guid><description>This post is largely a log so I remember how to do it next time, but if anyone else has a bunch of scans to convert, read on&amp;hellip;
Background Frequently in academia&amp;mdash;and probably in much of the modern world&amp;mdash;one has to handle things which began life as books, hit the glass of a scanner, and became pdfs. Scanning is hard, and unless one has a lot of patience, the resulting pdfs are generally pretty all over the place: sometimes pages are upside down, frequently the book (which was not made to lie flat) does not want to flatten on the glass, and often the scanner has simply picked a nearby standard page size.</description></item><item><title>Toaster</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/toaster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 21:01:29 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/toaster/</guid><description>Somebody has bent the toaster. It shouldn’t be looking like this:
It should be looking rather like this:
Oh well. It&amp;rsquo;s only mild steel and it bends easily. Some springs got out of place too, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to ping them all back, particularly with the unbent side for comparison. The hard thing is normally taking toasters apart&amp;mdash;cheapy ones are frequently held together with bent metal tabs, which sheer if you try to unbend them&amp;mdash;and of course it&amp;rsquo;s always messy.</description></item><item><title>Thermostat</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/thermostat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 20:44:46 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/thermostat/</guid><description>Our thermostat has an annoying feature. If you press any button&amp;mdash;but particularly the ‘OK’ button you have to press a lot to change anything&amp;mdash;it reboots. Worse, it loses everything you’ve just entered. Last night it started doing this without my pressing anything. I first thought a dead battery might be to blame, but even with a steady 3V from my bench power supply it refused to work. I put it aside, and when it came back on ten minutes later, very carefully increased the temperature till it turned on.</description></item><item><title>Microwave Repair and Volume Control</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/microwave-repair-and-volume-control/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 20:02:51 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/microwave-repair-and-volume-control/</guid><description>My microwave went on the blink, a few days before I got married. It started turning itself on, randomly, as soon as it was plugged in. You could use it&amp;mdash;I did in fact use it&amp;mdash;by putting something inside, waiting for it to turn on, and then opening the door after the required time had elapsed. Hardly ideal. I unplugged it and left it for later&amp;mdash;there were other things to think about after all&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Anti Rsi</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/anti-rsi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 18:12:00 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/anti-rsi/</guid><description>There are lots of anti-rsi packages out there for windows. I even found a few for Linux. None did what I wanted them to do: to enforce short and long breaks at configurable intervals, allowing me to push them back when I was in the middle of something, but getting increasingly insistent that I actually took them.
Enter anti-rsi, a python script which does everything an anti-rsi package needs to do and nothing more.</description></item><item><title>Webcam on and Off</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/webcam-on-and-off/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 17:17:55 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/webcam-on-and-off/</guid><description>Currently we are all stuck in front of webcams, at least half the time. I do have a laptop&amp;mdash;a gift from a kind friend&amp;mdash;and it does get used, but the rest of the time I am sitting before two old monitors (one of which recently had to be repaired) and a lovely cherry keyboard: and no webcam. No matter: I’ve a cheapo usb-thing and it works fine. I’ve also an old phone handset from an 80s landline wired into two 3.</description></item><item><title>Workbench: first shot</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/workbench/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 15:34:19 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/workbench/</guid><description>Background This workbench is built almost exactly to a published design and following the videos. One has to buy the videos. This is the first time I have ever done anything like this, and it was a very good idea. Buy them; watch them; copy them. Unless one is very lucky one simply doesn’t get to watch a good craftsman up close very often, but the ability to pause, zoom, replay, and see exactly how to position your hands and body when paring with a chisel, for example, is worth any amount of textbooks.</description></item><item><title>Volatile Tmp</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/volatile-tmp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 11:00:07 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/volatile-tmp/</guid><description>What does one do with temporary files? For things one really doesn’t need, there’s /tmp, which is wiped on boot&amp;mdash;though sometimes it’s a ramdisk, and one should be wary of dropping large files into ramdisks. But what about e.g. downloaded isos, pdfs prepared for printing, and the like? Things one needs now, might need tomorrow, but definitely won’t need in a year’s time?
Like most people I used to use ~/Downloads and go through it (with ncdu) every time it got too large.</description></item><item><title>CLI Countdown Timer</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/cli-countdown-timer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 13:05:10 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/cli-countdown-timer/</guid><description>I wrote this a while ago, and it’s been in use ever since: a very simple script which counts down (or up) while printing the remaining time. Controlled with standard job control, it’s one up on sleep as you can see how long is left. This is occasionally handy; if I only have ten seconds on the clock before lunch I’ll not start something new, but if I’ve got fifteen it might make sense.</description></item><item><title>Leaving Wordpress</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/2020-09-28-leaving-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/2020-09-28-leaving-wordpress/</guid><description>Wordpress is a glorious conglomeration of PHP which works very well, PHP which works poorly and PHP which doesn’t work at all. The former is generally written by the Wordpress developers, the next by me, and the latter by me after around 11pm.
This website existed for a while on wordpress.com. It was the natural choice: everyone uses wordpress to manage blogs, and this is little more than a blog. On the other hand, writing in a web browser is irritating (writing is what text editors are for) and does one really need the whole wordpress architecture to serve a lot of static pages and images?</description></item><item><title>Shaver Repair</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/shaver-repair/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/shaver-repair/</guid><description>My father’s electric shaver wasn’t holding charge; he asked if I could have a look at it and see if the internal battery could be replaced. Here’s the exploded view:
The green battery is a NiMH, not NiCad as I&amp;rsquo;d expected. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s not that old. Which is as well, as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any NiCads in the drawer when hunting around before, and was planning on gutting it and fitting a LiPo battery and tiny charging module.</description></item><item><title>Quick Sunrise Alarm Clock</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/quick-sunrise-alarm-clock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:42:14 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/quick-sunrise-alarm-clock/</guid><description>This was a sudden impulse last summer: I&amp;rsquo;d seen a &amp;lsquo;sunrise&amp;rsquo; alarm clock (which fades on slowly to simulate sunrise, theoretically bringing you out of deep sleep naturally and waking you up gently). My sister mentioned having difficulty getting up and needing multiple alarm clocks. Ergo.
First thought: where to get the light? I had a look in the LED parts draw, but it was disappointing, as was the draw of old led torches and bike lights.</description></item><item><title>Networked Clock with Hands</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/networked-clock-with-hands/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 22:48:29 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/networked-clock-with-hands/</guid><description>Dad rather liked my clock. In fact, he went looking for &amp;lsquo;a clock with hands and an adjustable chime&amp;rsquo;. Which, of course, made me wonder whether I could make one.
The first question was the hands: I liked the leds at the front of mine, and didn&amp;rsquo;t see the point in moving real hands around with a stepper motor or something of the kind. A digital clock should, I think, look digital.</description></item><item><title>Vertical Etching Tank</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/vertical-etching-tank/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:37:18 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/vertical-etching-tank/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t much like PCBs, but I like wiring ICs up even less. Up till now I&amp;rsquo;ve made boards with the toner-transfer-and-any-old-container method. The trouble is that I hate making up ferric cholride and always make the bare minimum, and during etching the concentration falls off, the rate slows, and you get poor definition and damage. So I decided to make a proper vertical etching tank, big enough to do a large board and still not run out of etchant.</description></item><item><title>Networked Alarm Clock</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/networked-alarm-clock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:23:04 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/networked-alarm-clock/</guid><description>This project began when the noise of the ethernet switch opposite my college room became unbearable. I picked the room for the view, which was sublime: the valley falls away so steeply you can see right down, over the trees, to the river, and climbs again the far side in a steeply wooded bank over which the pigeons perform what I can only describe as buzzing runs on the squirells. In the distance, the rolling hills, at night the moon and by day the sun—morning and evening, opposite corners of the window.</description></item><item><title>How to Move a Piano</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/how-to-move-a-piano/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:07:44 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/how-to-move-a-piano/</guid><description>Moving is not much fun. Moving pianos is even less fun: you have all the difficulty of moving a 300kg object coupled with the worry that you&amp;rsquo;ll twist it out of shape, drop it, strain it, or just shake it too much.
Moving, however, just round the corner—700yds, according to Google—is at least easier than moving halfway round the world. But moving a piano 700yds is not apparently any easier than moving it 300 miles: you can&amp;rsquo;t wheel it, not on those little coasters, or even on a furniture dolly.</description></item><item><title>How To Break a Freezer</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/how-to-break-a-freezer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 13:52:03 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/how-to-break-a-freezer/</guid><description>I arrived back yesterday to discover that the fridge, or more specifically the fridge-freezer, had been off for at least a week.1 The same week, coincidentally, that temperatures in the range of southern France on a cool day have lead to pantograph cables all falling off. Oops. Hopefully the repairs will be more heat-tolerant&amp;hellip; Thus in this heat wave2—well, it was certainly warm—the inside of the fridge/freezer got to goodness knows what temperature (fridges make good beer-brewing ovens, as google will show).</description></item><item><title>CoffeePot, short and stout; here's my handle...</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/coffeepot-short-and-stout-heres-my-handle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:44:05 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/coffeepot-short-and-stout-heres-my-handle/</guid><description>One should not over-brew one&amp;rsquo;s coffee. This is a fault (mea culpa) I occasionally commit. One should probably not use one&amp;rsquo;s coffee pot to reheat coffee, and if one does, one should pay some attention to how long it is on for. Else it will boil dry, and then that heat has got to go somewhere… In this case, it went into the handle, the silicone rubber seal between the two sections and the knob.</description></item><item><title>Piano Tuning Lever</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/piano-tuning-lever/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 11:05:15 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/engineering/piano-tuning-lever/</guid><description>I have a piano to tune. And also to restore: a few hammer shafts to bend, hammers to file, a bit of crud to clean out, bridle straps to replace, etc, etc. The piano cost £40 from Ebay and is in remarkably good nick, and any piano is better than none! But an out of tune piano is no good.
Now students, I feel, should not really spend money having their pianos tuned&amp;mdash;at least, not students of Theology.</description></item><item><title>Radio repair</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/radio-repair/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 13:55:22 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/radio-repair/</guid><description>The radio we use in the kitchen to make washing up bearable stopped working. Specifically, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn on, but the power LED was constantly flashing on and then fading off. What makes me think the power supply might have died? Lo and behold, after purchasing a cheap multimeter (it&amp;rsquo;s incredible how cheaply one can get some things now: in ten years the price of test equipment has plumetted): the &amp;lsquo;8v&amp;rsquo; output was about 3v, and the &amp;lsquo;15v&amp;rsquo; output was 0v.</description></item><item><title>PdfJam: for more than just pdfs</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/pdfjam-for-more-than-just-pdfs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 15:48:37 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/pdfjam-for-more-than-just-pdfs/</guid><description>Can we take a moment to remark on how wonderfully useful PdfJam is? Behind the scenes it&amp;rsquo;s just LaTeX. Thus you might be surprised to notice that
pdfnup --nup 1x1 --paper a5paper --no-landscape image.png Is an excellent way to turn an image—say, a bunch of screenshots of a page which you concatenated with
convert image1.png image2.png image3.png -append image.png Into (say) an a5 pdf, ready to be turned into a full-length pdf with</description></item><item><title>Bicycle Stand</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/bicycle-stand/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 12:04:33 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/bicycle-stand/</guid><description>After a few months of balancing my bicycle between two walls where once, it would seem, was a pantry, it got too annoying. Ideally one would like some kind of stand to hold the bike out the way, vertically. The internet turns up many such designs. After a trip around the rather poor selection of wood available at B&amp;amp;Q (the only place open), I settled on something slightly different—an L-shaped half-lapped frame with wooden chocks to space it, and the bicycle balanced with just a small inward turning moment counteracted by its own weight.</description></item><item><title>Napkin Rings</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/workbench/napkin-rings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/workbench/napkin-rings/</guid><description>One expects a student&amp;rsquo;s life to have a certain ascesis to it. One, for instance, does not buy rings for one&amp;rsquo;s napkin, one makes them. And so I procured some cord (the seller considered me carefully and then said that I had a face which permitted me to indulge in sailing, which in turn justified buying cord to tie knots—‘Sailors fiddle’, she said approvingly; though I cannot play the violin). And I procured a helpful video on the tying of 3-lead 8-bight Turks Heads, because I can never remember any of these fancy knots.</description></item><item><title>Clap-clap switch</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clap-clap-switch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 15:33:39 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clap-clap-switch/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought of those clap-activated switches as a bit of a gimmick&amp;mdash;after all, you can always just move the lightswitch if it&amp;rsquo;s that hard to get at. But currently my mother is hobbling around on crutches, and it suddenly struck me that turning the uplighter on from the doorway would be handy. A rummage through the junkbox found a board—I think from an old washing machine—full of relays, and 5v relays at that, so no need for a voltage multiplier to turn the relay on.</description></item><item><title>ChuffChuff (cheaply)</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/chuffchuff-cheaply/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 08:12:22 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/coding/chuffchuff-cheaply/</guid><description>On a rainy day here I wondered exactly when I should book a ticket up to Durham for another term. Most of the booking websites will help you, but not much: it&amp;rsquo;s tiresome to check a few days to see what the price variation is—and it can be fairly enormous. I was also curious as to what the long term trends might be: they don&amp;rsquo;t just seem to go down. All of which suggested some code to screenscrape all the tickets from somewhere and analyse them.</description></item><item><title>Compiling KiCAD/WxWidgets</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/compiling-kicad-wxwidgets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 20:52:36 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/compiling-kicad-wxwidgets/</guid><description>Since this has, alongside other things, occupied a whole day, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d put it up here in case anyone else tries. Back in the day KiCAD had a python scripting console. Currently that would be very useful: but it&amp;rsquo;s implemented with gtk2, and everything ships with wxwidgets compiled against gtk3. So we have to compile wxwidgets, which is fairly straightforward: get the sources compile&amp;mdash;except it&amp;rsquo;s not a ./configure, make, make install job: rather a python script calls other python scripts, and so on.</description></item><item><title>Basic Counter</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/frequency-counter/basic-counter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 16:04:41 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/frequency-counter/basic-counter/</guid><description>Now that we have a working counter and display the next thing to look at is the timebase. The timebase I built when first working on this counter is odd. It uses, for some reason, a 3.2768MHz crystal divided by (2^16 * 10n) to get a gate pulse which is a multiple of 1s, then further divided and decoded by a 3-to-8 decoder to generate pulses which latch the counter onto the display, and reset the counters.</description></item><item><title>'Off and on again' remotely</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/off-and-on-again-remotely/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 08:30:53 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/off-and-on-again-remotely/</guid><description>The internet in Durham, which was allowing me to use the workstation there remotely, has gone down; support tell me to &amp;lsquo;turn it off and on again&amp;rsquo;. But obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t do that remotely. Ah well, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really needed. But what if it were? I&amp;rsquo;ve run servers over unreliable wifi links with good uptime before, with a failsafe script which rebooted everything if it couldn&amp;rsquo;t ping the gateway for too long—and looking at the logs, sometimes it was needed.</description></item><item><title>Display Board</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/frequency-counter/display-board/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 16:02:59 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/frequency-counter/display-board/</guid><description>I started this peice of test equipment when I was about 15, I think, built the timebase with enthusiasm, the counting chain with a bit less, and then wondered how on earth I was to attach the 7-segment displays. Surely not one wire each?! So the project languished, and eventually got relegated to the shelf without ever being finished. All I had was the breadboard and two schematics which nearly corresponded with what was in front of me:</description></item><item><title>CD Player Line-In</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/cd-player-line-in/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/cd-player-line-in/</guid><description>This is a very simple project indeed: add a line-in input feeding the amplifier in my sister&amp;rsquo;s CD/Tape/Radio, which has much better sound than the &amp;lsquo;device&amp;rsquo; she mainly plays music from. How hard can it be to find the amplifier IC and feed in directly?
Taking the thing apart was none too hard, and it&amp;rsquo;s cheap &amp;rsquo;90s hardware so all through-hole and single-sided PCB. I found the mode switch, traced it back to the amplifier, paid careful attention to the pinouts and soldered a small cable onto one input, the other end going to a 555 &amp;lsquo;signal generator&amp;rsquo; kit I had lying around.</description></item><item><title>More bookbinding tools</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/bookbinding/more-bookbinding-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 08:12:14 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/bookbinding/more-bookbinding-tools/</guid><description>A while ago I made one of those vices used for bookbinding which is called a &amp;lsquo;lying press&amp;rsquo;, not because it is used to print articles for the Lügendpresse, whoever that might be, but because it is a press and lies down, in a bench called a tub. There are many drawings, etc, all over the internet. My press is a little different: I used old windowsill &amp;lsquo;mahogany&amp;rsquo;, and took advantage of the profile to make one side a &amp;lsquo;backing press&amp;rsquo; with protruding jaws planed away after a picture I found in an old book somewhere.</description></item><item><title>Proof of Concept</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/battery-charger/proof-of-concept/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 07:30:59 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/battery-charger/proof-of-concept/</guid><description>By this point we have all we need for a basic charge, and I do actually need to charge some batteries. I can build a simple current regulator with an LM317 and a resistor, which will be good enough for now.
No Termination The simplest thing would be just to charge some batteries and log to the computer. There&amp;rsquo;s a marvellous thing out there called FeedGnuPlot which makes graphing realtime or static data so easy one has to resist the temptation to graph everything.</description></item><item><title>PIC Development Board</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/pic-development-board/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 17:09:12 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/pic-development-board/</guid><description>As part of the Battery Charger project I need a basic PIC dev board. I built one a long time ago for A2 coursework, and I even found the artwork lying around, but the tracks and pads were too small for hand etching and drilling. Trying to open the cad files in KiCad I discovered that they&amp;rsquo;ve changed everything, and half the symbols &amp;lsquo;cannot be found&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve also completely forgotten how to use KiCad or schematic capture/Pcb design software in general: all pointing to a need to redraw.</description></item><item><title>Background</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/battery-charger/background/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 12:50:36 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/battery-charger/background/</guid><description>There are lots of &amp;lsquo;smart&amp;rsquo; chargers out there. Most of them boast that they can charge your batteries quicker than the competition, and that a &amp;lsquo;smart&amp;rsquo; algorithm will somehow prevent packing as much current as possible into a cell in the shortest time from having deleterious effects. Slow chargers are harder to come by: there are the cheap constant-current things you run for a certain amount of time—but if your batteries are not absolutely dead they will overcharge, and probably overheat and explode, as mine did.</description></item><item><title>Poor Man's Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/poor-mans-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 09:58:16 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/poor-mans-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>Embedded Linux is currently all the rage with little boards like the Pi running a full-fledged Debian just to flash a few LEDs. Now certainly, the Pi would find uses here, but it&amp;rsquo;s hardly cheap. What is cheap—or even free—is defunct wireless routers. They, too, are embedded systems running Linux. Unlike the Pi they have on-board wifi and an ethernet switch; the cpu isn&amp;rsquo;t usually too bad either. I also picked a few up for £0.</description></item><item><title>Vice Screw</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/workbench/vice-screw/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 15:17:33 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/workbench/vice-screw/</guid><description>About five years ago now I stopped dreaming of a proper bench vice and built one from some old oak kitchen doors I rescued from a skip, an old oak drawer, and long M6 bolts.
Some day if I find the pictures I might write it up as an example of how not to do it: I dovetailed the two runners on in opposite directions and a whole host of other things.</description></item><item><title>Repairing a Broken Tenon</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/repairing-a-broken-tenon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 14:54:31 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/repairing-a-broken-tenon/</guid><description>This posed something of a problem: what do you do when a pinned tenon breaks? The joint was too broken just to glue, neither surface was flat, and the dowels were in the way. In the end I decided to dowel it with three dowls, to leave as much of the broken tenon intact as possible. Dowled joints are easy on flat, square workpeices. On jagged tapering workpeices, now&amp;hellip; With a quarter-inch chisel I cut flats to mark on and marked the three holes on both mortice and tenon.</description></item><item><title>A lesson in Ferric Chloride</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/workbench/a-lesson-in-ferric-chloride/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 14:41:48 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/workbench/a-lesson-in-ferric-chloride/</guid><description>FeCl3 is that stuff we use to etch circuit boards; apparently there are other uses for it too. It etches most things, including, it would seem, the lid of the jar I kept spent etchant in, the M10 studding on the bench underneath, and most surprisingly for me—for my chemistry is rather rusty—the plastic cap of the clamp on the shelf in front of it.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the damage control: Ferric Damage: it really does etch.</description></item><item><title>Microwave repair</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/microwave-repair/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 14:24:34 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/microwave-repair/</guid><description>There is a nasty thing out there called &amp;lsquo;built in obsolescence&amp;rsquo;, which is supposed to cure the fact that most things are actually made quite well and would last a long time if left to themselves. Here is a microwave: Well at any rate, there&amp;rsquo;s most of a microwave. The &amp;lsquo;cancel&amp;rsquo; button was no longer working. What makes me think the entire microwave is being held hostage by a £0.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/page/about/</guid><description>Gardener Joe&amp;mdash;that great and renowned figure&amp;mdash;had a mouth like an &amp;lsquo;O&amp;rsquo;, but of what interest was that alongside his wheelbarrow full of surprises? This website resembles a wheelbarrow in several ways: it is no doubt full of (rather poor) surprises, generally of the how-not-to-do-things variety, it is all balanced rather precariously on one wheel and could pitch over any moment and make a mess, and it is liable to be forgotten for months and then overworked on a hot summer&amp;rsquo;s afternoon.</description></item></channel></rss>