<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Computing on Jack of All Trades</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/categories/computing/</link><description>Recent content in Computing on Jack of All Trades</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</managingEditor><webMaster>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://2e0byo.github.io/categories/computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Webcam on and Off</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/webcam-on-and-off/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 17:17:55 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/webcam-on-and-off/</guid><description>Currently we are all stuck in front of webcams, at least half the time. I do have a laptop&amp;mdash;a gift from a kind friend&amp;mdash;and it does get used, but the rest of the time I am sitting before two old monitors (one of which recently had to be repaired) and a lovely cherry keyboard: and no webcam. No matter: I’ve a cheapo usb-thing and it works fine. I’ve also an old phone handset from an 80s landline wired into two 3.</description></item><item><title>PdfJam: for more than just pdfs</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/pdfjam-for-more-than-just-pdfs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 15:48:37 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/pdfjam-for-more-than-just-pdfs/</guid><description>Can we take a moment to remark on how wonderfully useful PdfJam is? Behind the scenes it&amp;rsquo;s just LaTeX. Thus you might be surprised to notice that
pdfnup --nup 1x1 --paper a5paper --no-landscape image.png Is an excellent way to turn an image—say, a bunch of screenshots of a page which you concatenated with
convert image1.png image2.png image3.png -append image.png Into (say) an a5 pdf, ready to be turned into a full-length pdf with</description></item><item><title>Compiling KiCAD/WxWidgets</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/compiling-kicad-wxwidgets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 20:52:36 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/computing/compiling-kicad-wxwidgets/</guid><description>Since this has, alongside other things, occupied a whole day, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d put it up here in case anyone else tries. Back in the day KiCAD had a python scripting console. Currently that would be very useful: but it&amp;rsquo;s implemented with gtk2, and everything ships with wxwidgets compiled against gtk3. So we have to compile wxwidgets, which is fairly straightforward: get the sources compile&amp;mdash;except it&amp;rsquo;s not a ./configure, make, make install job: rather a python script calls other python scripts, and so on.</description></item><item><title>'Off and on again' remotely</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/off-and-on-again-remotely/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 08:30:53 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/off-and-on-again-remotely/</guid><description>The internet in Durham, which was allowing me to use the workstation there remotely, has gone down; support tell me to &amp;rsquo;turn it off and on again&amp;rsquo;. But obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t do that remotely. Ah well, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really needed. But what if it were? I&amp;rsquo;ve run servers over unreliable wifi links with good uptime before, with a failsafe script which rebooted everything if it couldn&amp;rsquo;t ping the gateway for too long—and looking at the logs, sometimes it was needed.</description></item><item><title>Poor Man's Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/poor-mans-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 09:58:16 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/poor-mans-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>Embedded Linux is currently all the rage with little boards like the Pi running a full-fledged Debian just to flash a few LEDs. Now certainly, the Pi would find uses here, but it&amp;rsquo;s hardly cheap. What is cheap—or even free—is defunct wireless routers. They, too, are embedded systems running Linux. Unlike the Pi they have on-board wifi and an ethernet switch; the cpu isn&amp;rsquo;t usually too bad either. I also picked a few up for £0.</description></item></channel></rss>