<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Repairs on Jack of All Trades</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/categories/repairs/</link><description>Recent content in Repairs on Jack of All Trades</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</managingEditor><webMaster>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://2e0byo.github.io/categories/repairs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Toaster</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/toaster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 21:01:29 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/toaster/</guid><description>Somebody has bent the toaster. It shouldn’t be looking like this:
It should be looking rather like this:
Oh well. It&amp;rsquo;s only mild steel and it bends easily. Some springs got out of place too, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to ping them all back, particularly with the unbent side for comparison. The hard thing is normally taking toasters apart&amp;mdash;cheapy ones are frequently held together with bent metal tabs, which sheer if you try to unbend them&amp;mdash;and of course it&amp;rsquo;s always messy.</description></item><item><title>Thermostat</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/thermostat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 20:44:46 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/thermostat/</guid><description>Our thermostat has an annoying feature. If you press any button&amp;mdash;but particularly the ‘OK’ button you have to press a lot to change anything&amp;mdash;it reboots. Worse, it loses everything you’ve just entered. Last night it started doing this without my pressing anything. I first thought a dead battery might be to blame, but even with a steady 3V from my bench power supply it refused to work. I put it aside, and when it came back on ten minutes later, very carefully increased the temperature till it turned on.</description></item><item><title>Microwave Repair and Volume Control</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/microwave-repair-and-volume-control/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 20:02:51 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/microwave-repair-and-volume-control/</guid><description>My microwave went on the blink, a few days before I got married. It started turning itself on, randomly, as soon as it was plugged in. You could use it&amp;mdash;I did in fact use it&amp;mdash;by putting something inside, waiting for it to turn on, and then opening the door after the required time had elapsed. Hardly ideal. I unplugged it and left it for later&amp;mdash;there were other things to think about after all&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Shaver Repair</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/shaver-repair/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/shaver-repair/</guid><description>My father’s electric shaver wasn’t holding charge; he asked if I could have a look at it and see if the internal battery could be replaced. Here’s the exploded view:
The green battery is a NiMH, not NiCad as I&amp;rsquo;d expected. I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s not that old. Which is as well, as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any NiCads in the drawer when hunting around before, and was planning on gutting it and fitting a LiPo battery and tiny charging module.</description></item><item><title>How To Break a Freezer</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/how-to-break-a-freezer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 13:52:03 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/how-to-break-a-freezer/</guid><description>I arrived back yesterday to discover that the fridge, or more specifically the fridge-freezer, had been off for at least a week.1 The same week, coincidentally, that temperatures in the range of southern France on a cool day have lead to pantograph cables all falling off. Oops. Hopefully the repairs will be more heat-tolerant&amp;hellip; Thus in this heat wave2—well, it was certainly warm—the inside of the fridge/freezer got to goodness knows what temperature (fridges make good beer-brewing ovens, as google will show).</description></item><item><title>CoffeePot, short and stout; here's my handle...</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/coffeepot-short-and-stout-heres-my-handle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:44:05 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/coffeepot-short-and-stout-heres-my-handle/</guid><description>One should not over-brew one&amp;rsquo;s coffee. This is a fault (mea culpa) I occasionally commit. One should probably not use one&amp;rsquo;s coffee pot to reheat coffee, and if one does, one should pay some attention to how long it is on for. Else it will boil dry, and then that heat has got to go somewhere… In this case, it went into the handle, the silicone rubber seal between the two sections and the knob.</description></item><item><title>Radio repair</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/radio-repair/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 13:55:22 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/radio-repair/</guid><description>The radio we use in the kitchen to make washing up bearable stopped working. Specifically, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn on, but the power LED was constantly flashing on and then fading off. What makes me think the power supply might have died? Lo and behold, after purchasing a cheap multimeter (it&amp;rsquo;s incredible how cheaply one can get some things now: in ten years the price of test equipment has plumetted): the &amp;lsquo;8v&amp;rsquo; output was about 3v, and the &amp;lsquo;15v&amp;rsquo; output was 0v.</description></item><item><title>CD Player Line-In</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/cd-player-line-in/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 12:11:45 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/cd-player-line-in/</guid><description>This is a very simple project indeed: add a line-in input feeding the amplifier in my sister&amp;rsquo;s CD/Tape/Radio, which has much better sound than the &amp;lsquo;device&amp;rsquo; she mainly plays music from. How hard can it be to find the amplifier IC and feed in directly?
Taking the thing apart was none too hard, and it&amp;rsquo;s cheap &amp;rsquo;90s hardware so all through-hole and single-sided PCB. I found the mode switch, traced it back to the amplifier, paid careful attention to the pinouts and soldered a small cable onto one input, the other end going to a 555 &amp;lsquo;signal generator&amp;rsquo; kit I had lying around.</description></item><item><title>Repairing a Broken Tenon</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/repairing-a-broken-tenon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 14:54:31 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/repairing-a-broken-tenon/</guid><description>This posed something of a problem: what do you do when a pinned tenon breaks? The joint was too broken just to glue, neither surface was flat, and the dowels were in the way. In the end I decided to dowel it with three dowls, to leave as much of the broken tenon intact as possible. Dowled joints are easy on flat, square workpeices. On jagged tapering workpeices, now&amp;hellip; With a quarter-inch chisel I cut flats to mark on and marked the three holes on both mortice and tenon.</description></item><item><title>Microwave repair</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/microwave-repair/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 14:24:34 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/repairs/microwave-repair/</guid><description>There is a nasty thing out there called &amp;lsquo;built in obsolescence&amp;rsquo;, which is supposed to cure the fact that most things are actually made quite well and would last a long time if left to themselves. Here is a microwave: Well at any rate, there&amp;rsquo;s most of a microwave. The &amp;lsquo;cancel&amp;rsquo; button was no longer working. What makes me think the entire microwave is being held hostage by a £0.</description></item></channel></rss>