<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clocks on Jack of All Trades</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/tags/clocks/</link><description>Recent content in Clocks on Jack of All Trades</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</managingEditor><webMaster>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 13:28:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://2e0byo.github.io/tags/clocks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sunrise Lamp</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/sunrise-lamp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 13:28:58 +0200</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/sunrise-lamp/</guid><description>Every project is a prototype, which calls out for a second version avoiding the mistakes of the former. The trick is to give the prototypes away; then one has a legitimate excuse to make another&amp;mdash;and one gains an (undeserved) reputation for generosity to boot. After the quick sunrise alarm clock various things happened, including a &amp;rsquo;two week lockdown&amp;rsquo; to build up capacity in the NHS, which turned into three months. Thus I was stuck in one part of London, and my fiancée in another, and the streets were patrolled by Dobermans with £10,000 fine notices stuck to their teeth.</description></item><item><title>Quick Sunrise Alarm Clock</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/quick-sunrise-alarm-clock/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:42:14 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/quick-sunrise-alarm-clock/</guid><description>This was a sudden impulse last summer: I&amp;rsquo;d seen a &amp;lsquo;sunrise&amp;rsquo; alarm clock (which fades on slowly to simulate sunrise, theoretically bringing you out of deep sleep naturally and waking you up gently). My sister mentioned having difficulty getting up and needing multiple alarm clocks. Ergo.
First thought: where to get the light? I had a look in the LED parts draw, but it was disappointing, as was the draw of old led torches and bike lights.</description></item><item><title>Networked Clock with Hands</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/networked-clock-with-hands/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 22:48:29 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/networked-clock-with-hands/</guid><description>Dad rather liked my clock. In fact, he went looking for &amp;lsquo;a clock with hands and an adjustable chime&amp;rsquo;. Which, of course, made me wonder whether I could make one.
The first question was the hands: I liked the leds at the front of mine, and didn&amp;rsquo;t see the point in moving real hands around with a stepper motor or something of the kind. A digital clock should, I think, look digital.</description></item><item><title>Networked Alarm Clock</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/networked-alarm-clock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:23:04 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/clocks/networked-alarm-clock/</guid><description>This project began when the noise of the ethernet switch opposite my college room became unbearable. I picked the room for the view, which was sublime: the valley falls away so steeply you can see right down, over the trees, to the river, and climbs again the far side in a steeply wooded bank over which the pigeons perform what I can only describe as buzzing runs on the squirells. In the distance, the rolling hills, at night the moon and by day the sun—morning and evening, opposite corners of the window.</description></item></channel></rss>