<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Carpentry on Jack of All Trades</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/categories/carpentry/</link><description>Recent content in Carpentry on Jack of All Trades</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</managingEditor><webMaster>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://2e0byo.github.io/categories/carpentry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wedding Carpentry</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/wedding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 18:01:17 +0200</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/wedding/</guid><description>Due to measures to combat the epidemic of bigamous marriages or something of the kind, we ended up having a wedding reception in the garden. Thus we needed tables, and benches, and things of the kind. Time to put the workbench to work.
Firstly there was a lorry:
Then there was a lot of wood:
The short pieces are legs for the benches; the longer will become benches and trestles (and will replace these horrible trestles I made earlier).</description></item><item><title>Carpentry Workbench</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/workbench2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 19:14:29 +0200</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/workbench2/</guid><description>The first shot at a workbench sat dormant for a fair while. Meanwhile it got cold&amp;mdash;very very cold. Then it got wet&amp;mdash;very very wet. Then it got hot&amp;mdash;very very hot. And how did my nice, carefully chosen unwarped 1&amp;quot; planks look after that? A pretty sorry state. Even the laminated legs had moved slightly (next time for lamination I need more glue). Then I discovered that I could get 6x2s from MKM building supplies.</description></item><item><title>Workbench: first shot</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/workbench/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 15:34:19 +0100</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/workbench/</guid><description>Background This workbench is built almost exactly to a published design and following the videos. One has to buy the videos. This is the first time I have ever done anything like this, and it was a very good idea. Buy them; watch them; copy them. Unless one is very lucky one simply doesn’t get to watch a good craftsman up close very often, but the ability to pause, zoom, replay, and see exactly how to position your hands and body when paring with a chisel, for example, is worth any amount of textbooks.</description></item><item><title>Bicycle Stand</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/bicycle-stand/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 12:04:33 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/carpentry/bicycle-stand/</guid><description>After a few months of balancing my bicycle between two walls where once, it would seem, was a pantry, it got too annoying. Ideally one would like some kind of stand to hold the bike out the way, vertically. The internet turns up many such designs. After a trip around the rather poor selection of wood available at B&amp;amp;Q (the only place open), I settled on something slightly different—an L-shaped half-lapped frame with wooden chocks to space it, and the bicycle balanced with just a small inward turning moment counteracted by its own weight.</description></item></channel></rss>