<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Battery Charger on Jack of All Trades</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/tags/battery-charger/</link><description>Recent content in Battery Charger on Jack of All Trades</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</managingEditor><webMaster>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://2e0byo.github.io/tags/battery-charger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Proof of Concept</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/battery-charger/proof-of-concept/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 07:30:59 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/battery-charger/proof-of-concept/</guid><description>By this point we have all we need for a basic charge, and I do actually need to charge some batteries. I can build a simple current regulator with an LM317 and a resistor, which will be good enough for now.
No Termination The simplest thing would be just to charge some batteries and log to the computer. There&amp;rsquo;s a marvellous thing out there called FeedGnuPlot which makes graphing realtime or static data so easy one has to resist the temptation to graph everything.</description></item><item><title>Background</title><link>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/battery-charger/background/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 12:50:36 +0000</pubDate><author>2e0byo@gmail.com (John Morris)</author><guid>https://2e0byo.github.io/post/electronics/battery-charger/background/</guid><description>There are lots of &amp;lsquo;smart&amp;rsquo; chargers out there. Most of them boast that they can charge your batteries quicker than the competition, and that a &amp;lsquo;smart&amp;rsquo; algorithm will somehow prevent packing as much current as possible into a cell in the shortest time from having deleterious effects. Slow chargers are harder to come by: there are the cheap constant-current things you run for a certain amount of time—but if your batteries are not absolutely dead they will overcharge, and probably overheat and explode, as mine did.</description></item></channel></rss>